Vladimir Bauer

DOB: 06 February 1981

Citizenship: Russia, Turkmenistan email: vbauerster@gmail.com

github: https://github.com/vbauerster

skype: vladimir.bauer4 phone: +79778642708



SUMMARY

Senior Software Engineer, with over 10 years of experience in IT industry. Quickly learn and master new technologies; successful working in both team and self-directed settings. Despite experience with several programming languages, I consider programming language as a tool for getting things done. I adhere to concept known as UNIX as IDE which helps me solving technical problems in a more efficient and fun way.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bankex, Moscow, Russian Federation Onsite work Senior Software Engineer September 2018 - January 2019

- · Programming languages used: Go
- Participated in design and implementation of high-load crypto exchange platform, which integrates with custody services and KYC services.
- Implemented MFA authorisation service and integration with others services.

SibEDGE, Moscow, Russian Federation AnchorFree, San Francisco, USA Remote work Senior Software Engineer May 2017 - August 2018

- · Programming languages used: Go, C
- Participated in design and implementation of vpn related microservices, such as DNS proxy server, vpn session tracking services (OpenVPN, strongSwan), benchmark services.
- Read many C code in order to re-write strongSwan's vici protocol in pure Go.
- Built pure Go solution to change Linux ipsets on the fly, which increased overall performance.
- Experienced with many Go libs, to name a few: GRPC/protobuf, miekg/dns, gorilla/mux, promotheus, gorm.

Raiffeisenbank, Moscow, Russian Federation Onsite work Software Engineer October 2015 - February 2016

- · Programming languages used: javascript
- Framework used: Aurelia, ReactJs
- · Participated in project refactoring as front end engineer.

Sberbank Technologies, Moscow, Russian Federation Onsite work

August 2013 - June 2015

Software Engineer

- Programming languages used: java, javascript
- · Framework used: Spring, AngularJs
- · Data base used: Oracle
- Participated in many projects, such as KVRB, QR-code payment systems, Mortgage calculation systems.

Schlumberger Logelco Inc, Balkanabat, Turkmenistan OnSite IT Support Level II

January 2005 - June 2013

- Implemented LAN architecture from the scratch. Media type used UTP Cat5e cable inside buildings and Fiber Optic cable to interconnect different buildings outside.
- Implemented Physical Access Control System (PACS) architecture based on Lenel OnGuard 2008 package.
- · Responsible for any LAN/WAN issues.
- Provided remote and on-site support for domestic and international customers.
- Managed a high-volume workload within a deadline-driven environment. Resolved an average of 100
 inquiries in any given week and consistently met performance benchmarks in all areas (speed, accuracy,
 volume).
- Participated in collaborate project as collaborate champion for a given location. Conducted preimplementation workshops, delivering group and individual training sessions and creating user-friendly
 training materials. As a result all users were migrated to the Exchange mail seamlessly, mass trainings
 helped to improve customer's satisfaction.
- · Maintained Asset Management.
- · Active participation in regular staff meetings.
- Have developed web based call accounting and monitoring software, which helped the company both to reduce costs and eliminate unauthorised outgoing calls.
- Have developed web based time attendance reporting system based on Lenel OnGuard 2008 database, which allowed personnel department to check hours of attendance of employees.

EDUCATION

International Turkmen-Turkish University (ITTU), Ashgabat, Turkmenistan Bachelor of science in computer engineering

1998 - 2003

CERTIFICATIONS

Softline, Baku, Azerbaijan Microsoft Certified Professional

2009

Pink Elephant, Paris, France ITIL Version 3 Foundation Certified

2008

OTHER INFORMATION

Languages:

- · Russian Native
- English Intermediate

Interest:

- Mechanical keyboards and alternate layouts, I'm fluent Dvorak typist.
- Open source software.
 Alternate routers firmware like OpenWrt and TomatoUSB.
- Bicycling.